Hugsney Ferreira

Data Scientist

 $London-UK \\ hugsneyjc@gmail.com$

www.linkedin.com/in/hugsney-ferreira https://hugsneyf.github.io/HugsneyPortifolio/

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Over 9 years of experience in data analysis plus 3 years working with Python, SQL, and Tableau. Throughout my career, I have honed strong skills in designing dashboards utilising Excel, for reports on a daily, weekly, and monthly basis. Moreover, I successfully built programs that automate various tasks, resulting in significant time savings. In addition to my degree in Business and in Software Engineering at Imperial College of London, I am currently pursuing a bachelor's degree in Data Science.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst GROUP NEXUS, LONDON

Feb 2023 - Present

Key Responsibilities:

- Responsible for managing reports, providing actionable insights.
- Handling large datasets with global car park operational data.
- Automation supporting with AppScript, Python and VBA.
- Creating interactive dashboards in Excel, Tableau and Looker.

Kev Achievements:

- Created a Python programs with Selenium automating refund process, saving the equivalent of 8 people's time and increasing accuracy.
- Automated reporting download processes using Selenium, resulting in a monthly saving of one week's work time for three team members.
- Conducted on Big Data analysis with Pandas, saving 4 hours weekly.
- Designed and implemented automated Macros on Google Sheets in JavaScript (AppScript), daily time saving of approximately 1 hour.
- Chosen by company-sponsored Software Engineering course, where I developed skills in agile methodologies, collaboration, stakeholder management, team player, sprints, and troubleshooting.

Electronic Compliance Officer HEALTH VISION UK, LONDON

Sep 2020 – Jan 2023

Key Responsibilities:

- Facilitated stakeholder communication across various teams, supporting nearly 400 carers to improve client experience and operational efficiency.
- Assessed data quality and risks, ensuring compliance with health and safety standards.
- Analysed large datasets, including over $10,\!000$ weekly calls, to extract insights and identify trends within the healthcare sector.

Key Achievements:

- Utilised Python and SQL to automate analyse from Mobizio and Access People Planner, time saving of 3 hours.
- Spearheaded the implementation of a text message system that reduced call volume by 40%, improving team efficiency and response times.

KEY TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages

- Python: Pandas, Selenium, OS, XlsxWriter, Numpy & Autopi GUI
- SQL: Data querying & manipulation
- Frontend: HTML, CSS & JavaScript
- Java & R: For data science

Data Analysis & Visualisation

- Tableau, Looker, Excel & Machine Learning (ML)

Automation & Cloud Computing

- Automation: Python, VBA & AppScript
- AWS, GCP, Azure, BigQuery & GitHub

OTHER SKILLS

- Soft Skills: Organisation, Strong problem-solving, Attention to detail, Leadership & Teamwork
- Languages: English | Portuguese | Italian | Spanish

Data Analyst - Accounts Payable CSC - ALGAR, MG, BRAZIL

Sep 2015 – Feb 2019

Key Responsibilities:

- Performed in-depth analysis of travel documents and receipts, created trend analysis and root cause investigation to ensure compliance with regulations.
- Captured and documented use cases and issues related to travel expenses.
- Collaborated with risk management team to analyse and mitigate potential risks associated with travel expenses, while also driving continuous improvement through People, Process, and Technology.
- Managed invoice entries and deadlines, leveraging PowerBI for data-driven insights. Allocated tasks efficiently within the team.

Kev Achievements:

- Conducted analysis that successfully reduced by over 15% the amount of expenses (around £150k per month).
- Streamlined the reserving process for employees within 5 days by creating new documentation formats.
- Automated reports saving 3 hours a day by using VBA to develop macros.

Facilities Manager – Volunteering SHALOM COLLEGE, MG, BRAZIL

Sep 2013 - Feb 2016

Key Responsibilities:

- Managed and maintained campus facilities, ensuring classrooms and communal areas were in optimal condition for both students and staff.
- -Coordinated resources for academic sessions and extracurricular activities.
- Oversaw student attendance data, ensuring accuracy and timely reporting for administrative use.
- Improved processes through Scrum methodology and reengineering.

Key Achievements:

- Launched campus-wide sustainability initiatives, which resulted in a 15% reduction in energy consumption monthly.
- Implemented a excel attendance counting, leading to a 40% reduction in errors and enabling better monitoring of student attendance.

OTHER PROJECTS

Frontend Projects

- <u>Travel Guide Website</u>: University project for an informative website that offers a clean and user-friendly interface. Utilised HTML and CSS.
- <u>Google Page Clone</u>: Recreated Google's homepage design to practice and showcase proficiency in HTML and CSS.

Application in Java

- <u>Java Application Development</u>: Developed application for coursework, keys are object-oriented, classes, inheritance (extends) and data handling.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

BA - Data Science and computing	2022
Birkbeck, University of London – UK	Present
Bootcamp - Software Engineer – Ranked 1 out of 310 students	2023
Imperial College London – Portfolio Certification - UK	2024
BA - Business, Accounting and Communication—First Grade	2008
University Center of Triangulo – Brazil	2013